SIMRAN ARORA

SIMINAIN ARORA

CONTACT | 770 624 4256

EMAIL | arorasim@upenn.edu

WEBSITE | Simran Arora's Website

LINKEDIN | Simran Arora

Master of City Planning candidate with three years of experience in urban design, planning and project management. Internship experience in demographic, economic & real estate analysis and geospatial data development. Interested in geospatial data science, visualization and mapping, and seeking full-time opportunities in the transportation planning, economic development and urban analytics industries.

EDUCATION

Philadelphia, PA

University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia PA, Expected May 2023

Master of City Planning, Concentration in Transportation and Infrastructure Planning

- Leadership: Councilwoman on Inter-Professional Women's Committee, Leadership for Penn Transportation Club
- **Projects:** Planning Studio for West Philadelphia Neighborhoods, Predicting Home Sale Prices for Philadelphia, Analyzing Origin-Destination Trends for University City in Philadelphia, Visualizing Philly's Crash Data

Academy of Architecture, University of Mumbai, Mumbai India, May 2018

Bachelor of Architecture

- Awards: PCERF Urban Design category winner (2018), Destech Challenge for Smart Cities (2018)
- Internships: Research Intern at World Resources Institute, Landscape Architecture intern for Green Space Alliance, Writing Intern for Indian Architect & Builder

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

U3 Advisors, Philadelphia PA, May 2022 - current **Graduate Intern**

- **Demographic, Economic & Real Estate Analysis:** Analyzed census, employment, migration and real estate data using R to build insights for downtown development. Organized data spatially using ArcGIS to build reports.
- Retail Demand Forecasting: Developed models based on ESRI Business Analyst reports for supportable retail
 square footage for a university town and a downtown neighborhood.

PolicyMap, Philadelphia PA, May 2022 - August 2022, 3 months Data Development Intern

- Data Development: Cleaned, processed and documented data in SQL and created pipelines for new datasets.
- **Updating Datasets:** Weekly & monthly data processing for the PolicyMap website for healthcare, housing and census-related datasets. Collaborated with production team to update data on the platform.

StudioPOD, Mumbai India, May 2018 - July 2021, *3 years* **Architect**

- Mixed Use Masterplanning: Led a 100 acre residential, low-density masterplanning project in Bangalore, India.
 Assisted in two ~70 acre mixed-used masterplans based on the concept of landscape urbanism. Designed detailed design reports, presentations and renderings.
- **Urban Design and Placemaking:** Assisted in a heritage precinct masterplanning project in Puri, India. Created several concept-level presentations for pedestrian zones, street designs, plazas and other public spaces in Mumbai and Pune.
- Advisory: Won the 'Eyes on the Canal' competition organized by GIZ and UDC, India, as part of a 5-person team. Worked on developing strategies based on participatory planning and placemaking to revive the Buckingham Canal in Chennai, India. The funding continued for a year to develop a comprehensive report. Worked presented at London Biennale, 2021 and International Architecture Biennale Rotterdam, 2021.

Partners for Urban Knowledge, Action & Research, Mumbai India, June 2018 - June 2019, 1 year Youth Fellowship Recipient (Part-Time Researcher)

• Research: Led a team of 8 Fellows to develop designs for spaces under flyovers. Studied negative spaces under flyovers in Mumbai, created and conducted surveys and interviews with surrounding communities to propose a design for one such space. All the work was compiled into a report: 'Studying Urban Voids'. This work was presented at the Tata Institute of Social Sciences in June 2019.

PROJECT: Comparing Factors for Bike Trip Generation for Philly & Boston

For Geospatial Data Science in Python class

- Cleaned and analyzed data using Python for Philadelphia and Boston's bikeshare systems to compare the factors that generate bike trips. Packages used: geopandas, hyplot, OSMnx, cenpy and sklearn
- Visualized correlations using maps and charts. Data used: Open data from Indego and Blue Bikes, Census data, weather data, amenities data from Open Street Maps. Created a web page to show results and analysis.

SKILLS

Transportation Planning R (STPLANR) | VISUM & VISSIM

Geospatial Data Analysis ArcGIS | Python | R | SQL | JavaScript | ESRI Business Analyst & Field Maps

Other Writing | Graphic Design